# **Rabo Yusuf**

raboyusuf94@gmail.com | LinkedIn Profile | Github Profile | Portfolio

#### **SUMMARY:**

Frontend Software Engineer with 3 years of experience working with different kinds of web technologies. Skilled in solving problems with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, React Native, Redux, SQL, and NodeJs. Focused on being a valuable part of any team I am on and believe in the team rising together. If one portion of the team needs help with a task, I have no issue jumping in to assist on anything required.

## **CERTIFICATION:**

- AlgoExpert Data Structures and Algorithms
- Nano Degree in React, Redux, and React Native

## **SOFT SKILLS:**

- Communication
- Teamwork
- Time Management
- Collaboration

#### **EXPERIENCE:**

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER

The Bulb Africa, Lagos Nigeria

April 2021- Present

- Reviewed project specifications, and design technology solutions that met or Exceeded performance expectations.
- Updated old code bases to modern development standards, improving functionality.
- Collaborated with management, internal, and development partners regarding software application design status and project progress.

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Freelance Colab, Kaduna Nigeria

Jan 2019 - March 2021

- Designed customized solutions for proposals to potential customers.
- Developed software for desktop and mobile operating systems.
- Designed enhancements and updates for subsystems of end-user applications software running on local, networked, and Internet-based platforms.

## **EDUCATION:**

Masters in Engineering (Mech. Eng., CGPA 4.38) Bayero University Kano.

Kano State, Nigeria

April 2015 – Aug 2018

**CONFERENCE:** 

Nov 2021

Build Stuff Hybrid | Decode Your Space